<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>tact.moe</title><link>https://tact.moe/</link><description>Recent content on tact.moe</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><copyright>Â© tactidact {year}</copyright><lastBuildDate>Wed, 17 Mar 2021 05:16:54 +0500</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://tact.moe/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Winter 2021 Anime Diary</title><link>https://tact.moe/2021/03/17/winter-2021-anime-diary/</link><pubDate>Wed, 17 Mar 2021 05:16:54 +0500</pubDate><guid>https://tact.moe/2021/03/17/winter-2021-anime-diary/</guid><description>&lt;p>Welcome to the first seasonal anime diary. I&amp;rsquo;ll be making these posts once every season to highlight some of the notable anime that caught my eye in the past season.&lt;sup id="fnref:1">&lt;a href="#fn:1" class="footnote-ref" role="doc-noteref">1&lt;/a>&lt;/sup> To write something about every show I watch would be quite an undertaking, so let&amp;rsquo;s just start with stuff that really left an impression on me. Where appropriate, I will endeavor to include content warnings for the shows themselves.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Any shows that have their titles suffixed with the ðŸ’® emoji have my strongest recommendation.&lt;/p>
&lt;h2 id="yuru-camp-season-2-">Yuru Campâ–³ SEASON 2 ðŸ’®&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>
&lt;style>figcaption {text-align: center;}&lt;/style>
&lt;img
loading="lazy"
src="https://tact.moe/images/winter-2021-anime-diary/yuru-camp-s2.png"
alt="Yuru Campâ–³ Season 2"
/>
&lt;/p>
&lt;p>A wonderful window into the world of casual camping, &lt;a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Laid-Back_Camp"
target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener"
>Yuru Campâ–³&lt;/a>
takes us on a journey across various campsites of Japan with its cast of young middle school students. Nadeshiko, a recent newcomer to the local town befriends the girls of the Outdoor Club, Aoi and Chiaki, and the solitary camper Rin. And through them she discovers the pleasures of this past time.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Traveling to peaceful and relaxing locations, this show distills the feeling of sitting down on a porch with a hot cup of cocoa on a lovely fall day. The nature visuals are striking and sublime, the characters energetic and thoughtful with chemistry and friendship that is truly wholesome and supportive. Season 1 comes in strong with a gentle wave of warmth and comfort that hooked me instantly, enveloping you in the feeling of joy that something as simple as a cup of instant noodles or some piping hot campfire cooking on a cool night can bring. It also incorporates elements of travelogue to introduce the viewer to the various equipment and tools that campers make use of, along with introducing you to best practices at campgrounds. Every episode is topped off with an end card that lists off pointers for some common camping etiquette and campsite rules.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>This advice is usually delivered via narration from &lt;a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Akio_%c5%8ctsuka"
target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener"
>ÅŒtsuka Akio&lt;/a>
in his usual dulcet tones. ÅŒtsuka also plays Rin&amp;rsquo;s grandfather in the show, who inspired her to pursue camping and her travels around the country to various campsites. With beautiful scenery, calming music and characters that steal your heart, anyone seeking a wonderfully charming and highly relaxing anime to watch would do well to enjoy both seasons of &lt;em>Yuru Campâ–³&lt;/em> and the &lt;em>Heya Camp&lt;/em> shorts that aired in between seasons.&lt;/p>
&lt;h2 id="wonder-egg-priority">Wonder Egg Priority&lt;/h2>
&lt;blockquote>
&lt;p>âš ï¸ CW: Suicide, self-harm, abuse, trauma, dealing with grief&lt;/p>
&lt;/blockquote>
&lt;p>
&lt;style>figcaption {text-align: center;}&lt;/style>
&lt;img
loading="lazy"
src="https://tact.moe/images/winter-2021-anime-diary/wonder-egg-priority.png"
alt="Wonder Egg Priority title card"
/>
&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Wonder_Egg_Priority"
target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener"
>&lt;em>Wonder Egg Priority&lt;/em>&lt;/a>
was a show that captivated me from the very first episode. The art style, the music and just the general vibe of how it establishes itself and introduces us to our first protagonist took my breath away. It deals with human grief and the complications of the entanglements of our lives in a complex and nuanced way.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>It is the story of four middle school age girls, whose lives have been marred by abuse and depression. Who have lost friends and those close to them to suicide and are learning to navigate how to go on living. The ways in which this show through its fantastical premise examines and explores the human states and emotions of its four protagonists made a deep impression on me. How it explores the role of abuse in the lives of children and how it impacts their sense of self, is something I&amp;rsquo;ve never seen captured before in anime. How they can learn to find something to live for again within themselves and each other and come back from a point of absolute despair and loneliness.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>It&amp;rsquo;s sad then that the show ends incomplete, having not explored or even made good on the bevy of promises it makes. Looking into the behind the scenes this appears to have been the result of poor scheduling and mismanagment on part of the production comittee. It&amp;rsquo;s for this reason that we got the unexpected mid-season recap episode. The true finale which was pushed off the airing schedule by that recap now appears to be scheduled to &lt;a href="https://twitter.com/WEP_anime/status/1376942895505178626?s=20"
target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener"
>premiere on June 29th&lt;/a>
.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>I might thus have to revisit the show at that time when I can evaluate it as a whole.&lt;/p>
&lt;h2 id="mushoku-tensei-isekai-ittara-honki-dasu">Mushoku Tensei: Isekai Ittara Honki Dasu&lt;/h2>
&lt;blockquote>
&lt;p>âš ï¸ CW: Trauma, abuse, bullying, sexual objectification&lt;/p>
&lt;/blockquote>
&lt;p>
&lt;style>figcaption {text-align: center;}&lt;/style>
&lt;img
loading="lazy"
src="https://tact.moe/images/winter-2021-anime-diary/mushoku-tensei.png"
alt="Mushoku Tensei"
/>
&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Based on the wildly popular web novel and the light novel adapted from it, &lt;a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Mushoku_Tensei"
target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener"
>&lt;em>Mushoku Tensei&lt;/em>&lt;/a>
seems at first to be another bog standard &lt;a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Isekai"
target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener"
>isekai&lt;/a>
,&lt;sup id="fnref:2">&lt;a href="#fn:2" class="footnote-ref" role="doc-noteref">2&lt;/a>&lt;/sup> and really it is just that. But what sets it apart from its ilk is that it takes the time to really establish its protagonist, Rudeus, and the world without rushing straight into the adventure part of the journey. Giving us a glimpse of how an adult reborn into a fantasy world with their memories intact would navigate it through careful exploration and experimentation over the course of their life.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>The world building and magic system are interesting and refreshingly eschew the video game metaphor that has become prevalent in isekai of recent years. The cast of characters is also quite charming and feel fully formed like they have a life and thoughts of their own beyond simply being a foil for the protagonist&amp;rsquo;s growth and development. The art design and animation also kicks up the gear and really impresses when it needs to in the early episodes to leave a solid impression. The water physics and the direction of the scene in episode 1 where Rudeus casts his first intermediate tier water spell as a child is &lt;a href="https://tact.moe/images/winter-2021-anime-diary/rudy-casts-water-magic.mp4"
>a sight to behold&lt;/a>
.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>I was in fact so taken with the universe of this show that I ended up over the course of a week and a half reading all ten volumes of the light novel that have been translated to English so far. The books really lend themselves well to incorporating the viewpoints of secondary characters and interweaving them with the main narrative and building a very concrete sense of the universe in the reader&amp;rsquo;s mind.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>The protagonist does have a tendency to be extremely lewd and forthright with his sexual objectification of women even underage ones, which is to be frank very disturbing and straight up creepy. A core element of this story is that he was a hikkikomori NEET as a result of being abused and violently bullied in middle school, thus in his past life he&amp;rsquo;s grown to be a stunted and twisted person lacking any semblance of true empathy for other people. While this is important context and the protagonist does appear at least over the course of the series to grow beyond this to an extent, it&amp;rsquo;s still disconcerting and dismaying to come across as a viewer in an otherwise really fun and excellent show. Being horny is cool and great, but sexually objectifying people and non consensually peeping on them or stealing their underwear is reprehensible. Despite these shortcomings however I do find myself having fond feelings towards and relating to certain aspects of Rudeus' personality. A problematic fave indeed.&lt;/p>
&lt;h2 id="non-non-biyori-nonstop-">Non Non Biyori: Nonstop ðŸ’®&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>
&lt;style>figcaption {text-align: center;}&lt;/style>
&lt;img
loading="lazy"
src="https://tact.moe/images/winter-2021-anime-diary/non-non-biyori-nonstop.png"
alt="Non Non Biyori: Nonstop"
/>
&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;em>Non Non Biyori&lt;/em> is nonstop bliss, that is all&amp;hellip;&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Well to expound a bit on that, this is the third season of &lt;a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Non_Non_Biyori"
target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener"
>&lt;em>Non Non Biyori&lt;/em>&lt;/a>
, the incredibly wholesome adaptation of the manga of the same name. It tells the tales of the daily escapades of an assorted group of schoolchildren of various ages ranging from elementary to high school living and playing in the small village of Asahigaoka. It at times makes me laugh, at other times it makes me want to cry, but always because it presents the mundanity of daily life in an extremely thoughtful and considered repose.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>It&amp;rsquo;s a prime example of the &lt;a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Iyashikei"
target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener"
>iyashikei&lt;/a>
&lt;sup id="fnref:3">&lt;a href="#fn:3" class="footnote-ref" role="doc-noteref">3&lt;/a>&lt;/sup> sub-genre of slice of life anime that I&amp;rsquo;ve come to so dearly cherish. Truly every time I watch an episode, I feel I&amp;rsquo;ve been made whole again. It&amp;rsquo;s an incredible tonic to the soul with a wonderful and brilliant cast of characters. Every shot of the verdant village scenery that is interspersed between events may appear mundane at first but are carefully and thoughtfully selected to punctuate and construct a reverie that calms and soothes the viewer.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>This series is firmly on the list of shows that I would wholeheartedly recommend to most anyone who is looking for some introspective solace and a good time in their lives.&lt;/p>
&lt;section class="footnotes" role="doc-endnotes">
&lt;hr>
&lt;ol>
&lt;li id="fn:1" role="doc-endnote">
&lt;p>Or so I intend to, hopefully I can actually do this somewhat regularly.&amp;#160;&lt;a href="#fnref:1" class="footnote-backref" role="doc-backlink">&amp;#x21a9;&amp;#xfe0e;&lt;/a>&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li id="fn:2" role="doc-endnote">
&lt;p>lit. &amp;ldquo;otherworld&amp;rdquo;, an entire genre in which a person from our world is displaced or reborn into a fantasy world.&amp;#160;&lt;a href="#fnref:2" class="footnote-backref" role="doc-backlink">&amp;#x21a9;&amp;#xfe0e;&lt;/a>&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li id="fn:3" role="doc-endnote">
&lt;p>lit. &amp;ldquo;healing type&amp;rdquo;.&amp;#160;&lt;a href="#fnref:3" class="footnote-backref" role="doc-backlink">&amp;#x21a9;&amp;#xfe0e;&lt;/a>&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;/ol>
&lt;/section></description></item><item><title>Apple M1 Macbook Air</title><link>https://tact.moe/2021/02/20/apple-m1-macbook-air/</link><pubDate>Sat, 20 Feb 2021 22:22:08 +0500</pubDate><guid>https://tact.moe/2021/02/20/apple-m1-macbook-air/</guid><description>&lt;p>So I&amp;rsquo;ve had an M1 powered MacBook Air, my first Mac, for close to over a month now. And it&amp;rsquo;s been a life changing experience.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>I&amp;rsquo;ve been considering the Apple ecosystem for quite a few years now. Having been using Windows for my desktop OS needs since as far back as I can remember, and Android for my mobile needs from the early days of the smartphone era kicked off by the iPhone in 2007.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>The first Mac that I came across in my youth, was a PowerBook G4 my cousin owned when I was 13 or 14. I&amp;rsquo;d sneak into his room while he was away to mess around with it and to play a few levels of Halo CE on it. I still have vivid memories of the artwork on the OS X box that came with it, with the bold and imposing X floating in front of a swirling purple galaxy.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>I&amp;rsquo;d been Mac curious since that first experience, and had a few run ins with Macs later which further piqued my interest. Sharing a few classes with someone in 2014 who had a 2011 13&amp;quot; MacBook Pro. Later helping a less technically savvy friend setup their brand new 2015 15&amp;quot; MacBook Pro.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>By 2017 I&amp;rsquo;d made up my mind that I would like my next computer to be a Mac laptop, but fortunately or unfortunately, that period was smack dab in the middle of the infamously unreliable butterfly keyboard era. That put at least the MacBook Pros out, since I was not willing to deal with an unreliable and finicky keyboard that I might have to bring in for costly service often. The MacBook Air at the time had been barely updated with minor dated processor spec bumps every few years and still had a non-Retina screen.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>So by the time the Air had been updated with the current modern redesign and the butterfly keyboard had been bid adieu on the Pro line, the Apple Silicon transition seemed imminent. So I waited. It came with a bang and it&amp;rsquo;s been everything Apple promised and more.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>I have the 2020 MacBook Air with Apple M1 chip with 8-core CPU, 8-core GPU, 16-core Neural Engine. It&amp;rsquo;s equipped with 16GB of unified memory and a 1TB SDD. From day one it&amp;rsquo;s been a consistent and snappy performer. Native apps open near instantly, with some heavier apps like Garageband or Affinity Photo taking a beat to open as you would expect on any system.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Intel apps running under Rosetta 2 upon first launch take a few bounces in the dock to launch that may seem to take unusually long, but every subsequent launch is speedy enough to be functionally indiscernible from native apps. The thing that&amp;rsquo;s surprised me most with regards to app support, is how well the vast majority of Intel apps simply run. And even for the few apps that have had issues, updates are coming faster than you&amp;rsquo;d think from developers. Of the vast majority of apps that I run, only a small handful have yet to ship an Apple Silicon build either in beta or stable channels&lt;sup id="fnref:1">&lt;a href="#fn:1" class="footnote-ref" role="doc-noteref">1&lt;/a>&lt;/sup>. Those apps being namely &lt;a href="https://discord.com"
target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener"
>Discord&lt;/a>
and &lt;a href="https://www.skype.com/"
target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener"
>Skype&lt;/a>
. Despite this, the M1 does a magnificent job of running them and making them feel close to if not entirely as responsive as native apps.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>I don&amp;rsquo;t think I can speak fondly enough of Rosetta 2 if I tried. It is truly a marvel of vertical integration that Apple was able to build hardware level emulation of Intel x86 into the M1. Granted it only supports x86-64 emulation, since Apple already dropped support for x86-32 apps across the board as far back as macOS Catalina last year. A clever move by Apple to take the PR blow early to make an easier time for themselves down the line&lt;sup id="fnref:2">&lt;a href="#fn:2" class="footnote-ref" role="doc-noteref">2&lt;/a>&lt;/sup>.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>We&amp;rsquo;ve all seen Craig demonstrate the instant wake of these new M1 powered Macs and I&amp;rsquo;m happy to say the claims are entirely factual. This MacBook is awake at all times thanks to the big.LITTLE architecture of the M1, the efficiency cores keep ticking away even with the lid is closed. And the screen lights up every time without fail as soon as the lid is parted even half an inch from the chassis.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>You can see this from simply checking your router&amp;rsquo;s DHCP client list. The MBA never drops off WiFi and is constantly connected, able to pickup Continuity and Handoff requests at light speed. With my Air asleep and tucked into a drawer I was able to send it a tab from Chrome on my desktop, and the next time I lifted the lid, a notification was already there waiting for me on the lock screen telling me my tab had been received. I had to just brush the Touch ID sensor and begin working without any friction whatsoever.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Even battery life, the ever present specter that haunts the lives of laptop users is refreshingly of little concern here. In the best case scenario where I was using largely native apps and performing mixed productivity tasks such as writing, browsing the web, watching streaming video, working on this website and teaching myself some Java in IntelliJ IDEA, I routinely got 12-13 hours of solid use of the 15 hours that Apple promises for web browsing on this machine. I&amp;rsquo;d expect this kind of endurance from an iPhone or iPad, but to get it from a MacBook is truly incredible and a game changer for how much work I can get done without nary a moment of battery anxiety. It&amp;rsquo;s so good in fact that sometimes I&amp;rsquo;ve questioned truly how much time has passed since I began working because the battery indicator on my menu bar is still completely full.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>The thing that makes this computer a joy to use, is not in fact it&amp;rsquo;s raw performance in terms of how high it can score on any synthetic benchmark or how fast it crushes a video encode or Xcode compile. It&amp;rsquo;s in how fluid and effortless it feels to use on a day to day basis. From every animation to interaction it responds to my inputs almost as if it&amp;rsquo;s read my mind and began launching that app or file before I even clicked on its icon.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Apple Silicon has brought to the Mac one of the core elements that made the iPhone and iPad a joy to use that the Mac lacked, the ability to be instantly responsive and always awake. Balancing performance and power efficiency in such a way to make it seem simply magical. And in no Mac is this better personified than in the fan less MacBook Air. It wakes instantly, does what you command in the blink of an eye dutifully, and never even makes a whisper doing so. Backed by the full capability of macOS, this is the most delightful computer I&amp;rsquo;ve ever used.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Nothing I&amp;rsquo;ve seen in Intel&amp;rsquo;s 10th generation lineup of thin and light laptops that I&amp;rsquo;ve tried comes close to even capturing this feeling. Don&amp;rsquo;t get me wrong, Intel laptops are also very good and capable computers. But at this point I think I&amp;rsquo;m led to the conclusion that at least as far as low power silicon is concerned, ARM is the answer. Apple has handily bested Intel in this segment, and I can&amp;rsquo;t wait to see what Qualcomm, AMD and others that are foraying into the ARM laptop space can come up with&lt;sup id="fnref:3">&lt;a href="#fn:3" class="footnote-ref" role="doc-noteref">3&lt;/a>&lt;/sup>. Not to mention what Apple has in the can for the next stage of their transition&amp;hellip;&lt;/p>
&lt;section class="footnotes" role="doc-endnotes">
&lt;hr>
&lt;ol>
&lt;li id="fn:1" role="doc-endnote">
&lt;p>&lt;a href="https://isapplesiliconready.com"
target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener"
>Is Apple silicon ready?&lt;/a>
is an excellent resource for quickly checking at a glance if apps or packages run natively, under Rosetta 2 or not at all on Apple Silicon. Since it is community run, it can sometimes be a bit behind so always double check the developer&amp;rsquo;s website if you can too for the most up to date information.&amp;#160;&lt;a href="#fnref:1" class="footnote-backref" role="doc-backlink">&amp;#x21a9;&amp;#xfe0e;&lt;/a>&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li id="fn:2" role="doc-endnote">
&lt;p>Similarly to how the headphone jack was removed on the iPhone 7 to suffer the negative round of headlines and press early rather than with next year&amp;rsquo;s iPhone X.&amp;#160;&lt;a href="#fnref:2" class="footnote-backref" role="doc-backlink">&amp;#x21a9;&amp;#xfe0e;&lt;/a>&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li id="fn:3" role="doc-endnote">
&lt;p>Dependent of course on if Microsoft can figure out their x86-64 emulation story. Currently even x86-32 emulation on Windows on ARM is significantly less performant than Rosetta 2 on the M1.&amp;#160;&lt;a href="#fnref:3" class="footnote-backref" role="doc-backlink">&amp;#x21a9;&amp;#xfe0e;&lt;/a>&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;/ol>
&lt;/section></description></item><item><title>Setting Custom Ringtones on iPhone</title><link>https://tact.moe/2020/11/14/custom-ringtones-on-iphone/</link><pubDate>Sat, 14 Nov 2020 13:20:40 +0500</pubDate><guid>https://tact.moe/2020/11/14/custom-ringtones-on-iphone/</guid><description>&lt;p>If you have an iPhone and want to set a custom ringtone, there are a few ways to accomplish this, none of them however are logical or sane. The method outlined here also works on iPad, iPod Touch or any other iOS device and should apply to anything running iOS 12 through to 14 or later.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>The easiest and my preferred method is to make use of GarageBand on iOS. There are other methods such as using Finder on macOS or iTunes on Windows, but those require that you either have your phone synced to that specific computer or that you have the &amp;ldquo;Manually manage media&amp;rdquo; setting toggled on for your iPhone in iTunes. And since iTunes is going the way of the dodo, that particular&lt;sup id="fnref:1">&lt;a href="#fn:1" class="footnote-ref" role="doc-noteref">1&lt;/a>&lt;/sup> method may not be around for much longer.&lt;/p>
&lt;h2 id="the-method">The method&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>First of all you need to have &lt;a href="https://apps.apple.com/us/app/garageband/id408709785"
target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener"
>GarageBand for iOS&lt;/a>
on your phone&lt;sup id="fnref:2">&lt;a href="#fn:2" class="footnote-ref" role="doc-noteref">2&lt;/a>&lt;/sup>. Next ensure you have the audio file that you wish to make a ringtone accessible in the Files app. You can do this by just dropping it into iCloud Drive from a Mac or PC or any other device, or if you&amp;rsquo;re running iOS 13 or later, you can download the file directly from a the web in Safari. Your audio file can be an AIFF, WAV, CAF, Apple Loops, AAC, MP3 or MIDI file.&lt;/p>
&lt;ol>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>Open GarageBand for iOS and tap &amp;ldquo;Create Song&amp;rdquo;.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>
&lt;style>figcaption {text-align: center;}&lt;/style>
&lt;img
loading="lazy"
src="https://tact.moe/images/GarageBand-Create-Song.JPEG"
alt="Tap &amp;amp;ldquo;Create Song&amp;amp;rdquo; in GarageBand"
/>
&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>Swipe through the options till you find the Audio Recorder section and tap the &amp;ldquo;Voice&amp;rdquo; icon.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>
&lt;style>figcaption {text-align: center;}&lt;/style>
&lt;img
loading="lazy"
src="https://tact.moe/images/GarageBand-Audio-Recorder.PNG"
alt="Tap the &amp;amp;ldquo;Voice&amp;amp;rdquo; icon on Audio Recorder"
/>
&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>On the screen that appears tap the timeline editor icon highlighted in the image below.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>
&lt;style>figcaption {text-align: center;}&lt;/style>
&lt;img
loading="lazy"
src="https://tact.moe/images/GarageBand-Timeline-Icon.PNG"
alt="Tap the timeline editor icon"
/>
&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>In the timeline editor view, tap the Loops icon highlighted in the image.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>
&lt;style>figcaption {text-align: center;}&lt;/style>
&lt;img
loading="lazy"
src="https://tact.moe/images/GarageBand-Timeline-Loops-Icon.PNG"
alt="Tap the Loops icon in the timeline editor"
/>
&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>Tap &amp;ldquo;Browse items from the Files app&amp;rdquo;. You can also clip a portion of a song from the Music app from your locally synced music. Once the clip you&amp;rsquo;ve selected appears in this menu, you can tap and hold the file and drag it onto the timeline.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>
&lt;style>figcaption {text-align: center;}&lt;/style>
&lt;img
loading="lazy"
src="https://tact.moe/images/GarageBand-Browse-Files.PNG"
alt="Tap the &amp;amp;ldquo;Browse items from the Files app&amp;amp;rdquo;"
/>
&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>Cut/trim the audio as needed and then exit the editor by tapping the inverted chevron in the top left and tapping &amp;ldquo;My Songs&amp;rdquo;.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>
&lt;style>figcaption {text-align: center;}&lt;/style>
&lt;img
loading="lazy"
src="https://tact.moe/images/GarageBand-My-Songs.PNG"
alt="Tap the &amp;amp;ldquo;My Songs&amp;amp;rdquo;"
/>
&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>Tap and hold on your newly created GarageBand project file and tap &amp;ldquo;Share&amp;rdquo;.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>
&lt;style>figcaption {text-align: center;}&lt;/style>
&lt;img
loading="lazy"
src="https://tact.moe/images/GarageBand-Tap-Share.PNG"
alt="Tap and hold project file and tap &amp;amp;ldquo;Share&amp;amp;rdquo;"
/>
&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>Tap &amp;ldquo;Ringtone&amp;rdquo; from the options presented, name it and hit &amp;ldquo;Export&amp;rdquo;.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>
&lt;style>figcaption {text-align: center;}&lt;/style>
&lt;img
loading="lazy"
src="https://tact.moe/images/GarageBand-Tap-Ringtone.PNG"
alt="Tap &amp;amp;ldquo;Ringtone&amp;amp;rdquo;"
/>
&lt;/p>
&lt;p>
&lt;style>figcaption {text-align: center;}&lt;/style>
&lt;img
loading="lazy"
src="https://tact.moe/images/GarageBand-Tap-Export.PNG"
alt="Name and tap &amp;amp;ldquo;Export&amp;amp;rdquo;"
/>
&lt;/p>
&lt;p>
&lt;style>figcaption {text-align: center;}&lt;/style>
&lt;img
loading="lazy"
src="https://tact.moe/images/GarageBand-Exporting-Ringtone.PNG"
alt="Exporting as Ringtone&amp;amp;hellip;"
/>
&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>You can use the imported ringtone for calls, texts or assign it just to a specific contact. You can also just dismiss this by pressing &amp;ldquo;Done&amp;rdquo; and go to &lt;em>Settings â†’ Sounds &amp;amp; Haptics â†’ Ringtone&lt;/em> and assign the newly imported ringtone as you like.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>
&lt;style>figcaption {text-align: center;}&lt;/style>
&lt;img
loading="lazy"
src="https://tact.moe/images/GarageBand-Ringtone-Export-Successful.PNG"
alt="Ringtone Export Successful"
/>
&lt;/p>
&lt;p>
&lt;style>figcaption {text-align: center;}&lt;/style>
&lt;img
loading="lazy"
src="https://tact.moe/images/GarageBand-Assign-Ringtone.PNG"
alt="Assign ringtone"
/>
&lt;/p>
&lt;p>
&lt;style>figcaption {text-align: center;}&lt;/style>
&lt;img
loading="lazy"
src="https://tact.moe/images/Settings-Sounds-Ringtones.PNG"
alt="&amp;lt;em&amp;gt;Settings â†’ Sounds &amp;amp;amp; Haptics â†’ Ringtone&amp;lt;/em&amp;gt;"
/>
&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;/ol>
&lt;p>And there you go, you now have a custom ringtone imported to your iPhone. Sadly these ringtones that you import do not sync across to all your devices signed into the same Apple ID, but once you have the GarageBand project files in iCloud Drive it&amp;rsquo;s trivially easy to do so in a few taps on your iPad or any other device.&lt;/p>
&lt;section class="footnotes" role="doc-endnotes">
&lt;hr>
&lt;ol>
&lt;li id="fn:1" role="doc-endnote">
&lt;p>And frankly much more arduous&amp;#160;&lt;a href="#fnref:1" class="footnote-backref" role="doc-backlink">&amp;#x21a9;&amp;#xfe0e;&lt;/a>&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li id="fn:2" role="doc-endnote">
&lt;p>Which is approximately a 1.6 GB download, a frankly insane amount of storage to have to dedicate to an app I only keep around to set ringtones on a whim.&amp;#160;&lt;a href="#fnref:2" class="footnote-backref" role="doc-backlink">&amp;#x21a9;&amp;#xfe0e;&lt;/a>&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;/ol>
&lt;/section></description></item><item><title>Apple Silicon</title><link>https://tact.moe/2020/10/10/apple-silicon/</link><pubDate>Sat, 10 Oct 2020 03:28:08 +0500</pubDate><guid>https://tact.moe/2020/10/10/apple-silicon/</guid><description>&lt;p>At WWDC 2020, Apple announced the transition of the Mac from Intel processors to to their own &amp;ldquo;Apple Silicon&amp;rdquo; processors, the same kind as the ARM based chips that power the iPhone and iPad. They also commited to shipping their first Mac with these chips before the end of 2020 and said that they intend the transition to last two years.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Apple&amp;rsquo;s initial Mac Silicon is to be based around its A14 Bionic SoC that&amp;rsquo;s fabricated on TSMC&amp;rsquo;s 5nm process and debuted in their 4th generation iPad Air and will feature in the upcoming 2020 iPhones.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>This has ignited a firestorm&lt;sup id="fnref:1">&lt;a href="#fn:1" class="footnote-ref" role="doc-noteref">1&lt;/a>&lt;/sup> of renewed interest and frenzy around the Mac which in recent years seemed like it&amp;rsquo;d been left to languish in maintenance mode as Apple turned their affectionate gaze to the much more profitable iPhone and iPad as the future of computing. Now it might just get the rebirth it so rightly deserves.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Apple&amp;rsquo;s A series SoCs have for quite some time now been handily crushing Intel&amp;rsquo;s x86 processors and Qualcomm&amp;rsquo;s ARM SnapDragon SoCs in synthetic benchmarks like Geekbench. So this naturally an extremely exciting prospect and I&amp;rsquo;m very much looking forward to the kind of performance these SoCs can deliver in an enclosure with some actual active cooling on it.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>The ability that these new Macs will gain to be able to natively run iPad apps is also a welcome development. No longer will macOS be just the ancestor from whose underpinnings iOS sprang forth and was fashioned and molded into what it is today, but the Mac can now proudly stand at the head of Apple&amp;rsquo;s computers as the superset of all the software architecture that powers their ecosystem.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>There is of course the concern as to whether Rosetta 2 will be sufficiently performant on Apple Silicon when running apps and utilities that are still x86. But early hush hush nods from developers who have access to the DTK suggest that things are looking up in that department and that near native performance can be expected for most tasks. The loss of Boot Camp and virtualization of x86 Windows on these new Macs will for now be a bit of a bummer and it&amp;rsquo;s yet to be seen whether Microsoft&amp;rsquo;s push for Windows on ARM and its x86 emulation layers will be as smooth sailing as Big Sur and Rosetta 2 seem like they might just be.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Apple is expected per &lt;a href="https://www.macrumors.com/2020/10/09/apple-silicon-mac-release-timeframe/"
target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener"
>Mark Gurman at Bloomberg&lt;/a>
to debut the first Apple Silicon Mac, which is to be a Macbook, at an event in November&lt;sup id="fnref:2">&lt;a href="#fn:2" class="footnote-ref" role="doc-noteref">2&lt;/a>&lt;/sup>. Rumors suggest that first in line to get the new silicon will likely be either the MacBook Air or a revival of the 12&amp;quot; MacBook, now finally matched with a processor that can handle itself in its razor thin and feather light chasis. We may also get an update to the 13&amp;quot; MacBook Pro. I&amp;rsquo;ll be very intrigued to see if Apple keeps up the dichotomoy in that particular Mac with a 2 port option as a more affordable but slightly lower power version and a 4 port version at a much higher starting price.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Whatever Apple debuts, my one and only plea and hope for them is that they learned their lesson with the 2015 12&amp;quot; MacBook. And that whether they choose it or the Air to be the new consumer Mac laptop, they grace it with &lt;strong>ports&lt;/strong> and not just in the singular&lt;sup id="fnref:3">&lt;a href="#fn:3" class="footnote-ref" role="doc-noteref">3&lt;/a>&lt;/sup>.&lt;/p>
&lt;section class="footnotes" role="doc-endnotes">
&lt;hr>
&lt;ol>
&lt;li id="fn:1" role="doc-endnote">
&lt;p>&lt;em>geddit?&lt;/em>&amp;#160;&lt;a href="#fnref:1" class="footnote-backref" role="doc-backlink">&amp;#x21a9;&amp;#xfe0e;&lt;/a>&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li id="fn:2" role="doc-endnote">
&lt;p>Come on give it to me already!&amp;#160;&lt;a href="#fnref:2" class="footnote-backref" role="doc-backlink">&amp;#x21a9;&amp;#xfe0e;&lt;/a>&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li id="fn:3" role="doc-endnote">
&lt;p>Oh and maybe don&amp;rsquo;t make the jump up to 16 gigs of RAM and a 512 gig SSD cost $400 or more kthxbye&amp;#160;&lt;a href="#fnref:3" class="footnote-backref" role="doc-backlink">&amp;#x21a9;&amp;#xfe0e;&lt;/a>&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;/ol>
&lt;/section></description></item><item><title>First Post</title><link>https://tact.moe/2020/09/15/first-post/</link><pubDate>Tue, 15 Sep 2020 18:06:00 +0500</pubDate><guid>https://tact.moe/2020/09/15/first-post/</guid><description>&lt;p>Welcome to a first post that isn&amp;rsquo;t really about much of anything. This will be a blog where I write about anime, tech and other assorted interests. I&amp;rsquo;m &lt;a href="https://twitter.com/tactidact"
target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener"
>tact&lt;/a>
and I intend to post to this blog &lt;em>semi-regularly&lt;/em>, or whenever I have something to say I guess.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Au revoir for now ðŸ‘‹, check here for new posts soonâ„¢ ðŸ¤ž.&lt;/p></description></item></channel></rss>